You keep talking about the population, but you mentioned cohorts earlier too.
你刚才一直在说总体 但之前你还提到了队列
What's the difference?
它们有什么区别？
>> Well, in the population you have a whole group of users.
总体包含一个完整的用户群体
But within that population you can define what's called a cohort.
但是你可以定义这个总体中的哪些部分是列队
And typically, this means people who enter the experiment at the same time.
通常而言 这表示同时进入实验的人
So for example, if you just divert by cookie or
例如 如果你按 cookie 或用户 ID 分组
a user ID, and you look at this particular country.
而且关注这个特定国家
Now, you may have all kinds of problems during the span of your experiment where
在实验过程时 你可能遇到各种问题
people come who come in classified as that country,
可能有归类为该国家的新用户加入实验
either drop out of the experiment, or potentially even for mechanical reasons,
可能有用户退出实验 还可能因机制原因失去一些用户
like their IP gets reclassified into a different geographic region.
例如用户的 IP 被重新归类至不同的地理区域
So you can lose users, and gain users, and
这可能导致用户减少 也可能导致用户增加
have users who've been exposed to the experiment for different period of time.
而且有些用户参与实验的时长还不一样
So cohort usually means that you define an entering class and you only look at
在使用列表时 你要定义一个进入类别
users who entered your experiment on both sides around the same time, and
然后仅关注大约在相同时间加入实验组和对照组的用户
you go forward from there.
并从那个时间开始进行实验
You could also use different information, so
你还可以使用不同信息
you don't look at people who join later, right?
你不关注在此后加入的用户 对吧？
You start with your initial group, and you can also use other information.
你从最初的群组开始实验 也可以使用其他信息
Like, if you want to know that oh,
例如 如果你想了解
these are users who've used your site consistently for the last two months.
最近两个月一直在使用你的网站的用户
Or who have both a mobile and a desktop associated with their user ID,
或者用户 ID 同时关联了移动设备和桌面设备的用户
you can use all of that to define a cohort.
你可以使用所有这种信息来定义队列
>> Okay, and when would you want to use populations versus cohorts?
好的 那么你什么时候使用总体 什么时候使用队列？
>> Well, cohorts are harder to analyze, and
列队更难以分析
they're going to take more data because you'll lose users.
因为用户会减少 所以你需要更多数据
So typically, you only want to use them when you're looking for user stability.
通常而言 你仅会在观察用户稳定性时使用队列
So say, you have a learning effect or you want to measure something like
例如 观察学习效果
increased usage of the site or increased usage of a mobile device.
或者衡量网站使用的增加情况或者移动设备使用的增加情况
Those are cases where you really want to see if your change had
在这些例子中 你会希望根据用户历史表现
a real effect on their behavior relative to their history.
了解你所做的更改是否对用户的行为产生了重大影响
And then you want a cohort.
这时候你可以用列队
If you don't need those types of metrics,
如果不需要用到这些类型的指标
then you can probably stick with the population.
那最好还是使用总体
>> Got it.
明白了